# Felix Sargent

San Francisco, CA felix.sargent@gmail.com - 415-860-6970 - https://felixsargent.com

## Profile

I'm Felix Sargent, an experienced Engineering manager. Since working at Rackspace as a Software Engineer, I have focused on managing and growing productive, highly-collaborative teams. I believe teams work best when they feel safe, and are well equipped for their challenging work.

I specialize in engineering management around platform infrastructure, developer tools, and product backends. I code in Javascript/TypeScript and Python, but I am comfortable leading a team in any language.

# Experience

# Sr. Engineering Manager @ <u>Truework</u>

#### Oct 2021 - Oct 2022

- Managed the Interfaces (FE App, API, TrueworkJS Widget (like Plaid), <u>Encompass</u> Integration) and Infrastructure teams (Django Python BE, TypeScript React FE)
- Hired 10 engineers and 3 interns. Directly managed 11 individual contributors
- Led the "API First" strategic initiative to create a first-class external developer experience
- Renegotiated contracts with Optimizely, Stoplight and Segment to keep costs lean as we expanded the team
- Revamped Front End and Backend recruiting, interviews structure, and hiring processes
- Transitioned a hard-working but unstructured team to use modern agile processes
- Coached underperforming team members up and through promotion

# Sr. Engineering Manager, University @ Atlassian

## May 2020 - Oct 2021

- Technical Architect of Atlassian University, Atlassian's customer education platform (Intellum)
- Performed market research on the e-learning space, working with vendors and gathering detailed requirements to migrate from legacy systems to a new vendor
- Worked to a hard deadline to migrate existing learning data to our new platform, developing integrations with Atlassian's existing system
- When needed, I dived into the code (Python, with Pandas and API integrations)
- Engineering Manager for the Training for Jira marketplace addon
- Managed a team of contractors to deliver the Training for Jira marketplace add-on.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to migrate a legacy project to a new system. Used analytics to prioritize work, and liaised with multiple third
  parties.

# Director of Engineering, Campaigns & API Usability @ MediaMath

## November 2016 - April 2020

- Managed 15 Engineers over two teams (Perl, NodeJS, Python)
- Supported the team's migration to CI/CD, reducing test and deployment time from days to minutes and reducing server costs for QA environments by 85%
- Facilitated the migration of authentication services to OAuth across the platform, enabling MFA, and improving security and customer experience
- Advocated for and implemented <u>Feature Flagging</u> platform wide
- Oversaw the transformation of the MediaMath API portal, transforming REST API customer experience with a fanatically positive response
- Implemented Open Source license compliance regulatory schemes with <u>Fossa.io</u> enabling the close of a multi-million-dollar credit facility from Goldman Sachs

# VP of Product @ GovOS (SeamlessDocs)

#### November 2015 - November 2016

- Led the product team with a philosophy of servant leadership to encourage discussion, healthy debate, and clear communication
- Created product strategy and worked with CEO and VP Eng. to set the road map to replace unreliable legacy systems (PHP -> Scala, JS/React)
- Managed recruiting and hiring for the Engineering team, scaling from 3 to 15 engineers
- Re-established trust between engineering and sales teams by establishing consistency, stabilizing the platform, and getting bugs closed
- Developed process for the account management team to triage and prioritize customer issues bringing median resolution time down by 80%, and increasing customer NPS scores by 60%
- Conducted extensive user research with government officials to refine product features and specifications
- Re-negotiated contractual obligations with customers to reduce commitments, and align engineering road map with company direction

# Sr. Product Manager, Vault @ Bloomberg

#### October 2014 - November 2015

- Product owner for Bloomberg Vault Surveillance, the communications monitoring and auditing tool for the Bloomberg Terminal (MCMP, BVTP)
- Implemented technology and policies to capture communications to prevent Market Abuse, Insider Trading, Harassment, and Data Loss
- Coordinated a team working on the latest and greatest technology stack including Scala, Play, Accumulo, & Akka running on a Mesos infrastructure
- Worked with Compliance and Security Officers to ensure the data integrity of our clients, and the Bloomberg Terminal

# Engineer / Product Manager@ Rackspace

## August 2011 - October 2014

- Product owner for Rackspace Autoscale (Python, Twisted)
- Initially an Engineer on the Autoscale team, and was promoted to Technical PM
- Defined the product strategy, roadmap, user stories, KPIs, and priorities
- Product owner for Repose (Java), an API Middleware Platform
- Repose handles Authentication (Openstack Keystone), Security, Rate Limiting, and Content Normalization for nearly all Rackspace APIs
- Presented Repose, the Openstack API Filter at OpenStack 2014
- Built the office <u>Kegerator</u>

# Projects

Mechanical Keyboards - So many mechanical keyboards.

BARTSign - Raspberry Pi Based Transit Board

Fippi - Physical internet radio, and Air Quality Monitor

My Voice is My Passport (eg 1992 movie Sneakers) - Voice Recognition Passwords for Condo Entry

#### Volunteer Work

# Chair of the Board @ Center for Election Science

#### 2017 - Current

A non-profit organization dedicated to improving the way we vote

- CES changed the way Fargo, ND, and St. Louis, MO elect their leaders
- Recruit new board members, coordinate strategic donors, and raise grants for the organization
- Wrote <u>Berkeley's City Council's switch to 're-weighted range voting' adds fairness to the system</u> (Berkeleyside)

# Mentor @ The Product Group

#### 2015 - 2017

- Recognized with the Outstanding Product Mentor Award
- Managing Technical Debt (July 17, 2016)
- How to Interview a Product Manager (February 7, 2016)
- Inheriting a Project (July 8, 2015)

# Founded the San Francisco Brigade @ Code for America

#### 2013

- Reformed the way <u>San Francisco Citizens without bank accounts get access to financial services</u>
- Brought the City Administrative Code online

# Education

# BA, Economics @ San Francisco State University

President, Economics Students Association

Treasurer, Pre-Law Society

Varsity Intercollegiate Policy Debate Team

# Links

Github: <a href="https://github.com/fsargent">https://github.com/fsargent</a>
Blog: <a href="https://medium.com/@antagonist/">https://medium.com/@antagonist/</a>
LinkedIn: <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/felixsargent/">https://linkedin.com/in/felixsargent/</a>
Keybase: <a href="https://keybase.io/fsargent">https://keybase.io/fsargent</a>